本字幕由诸神字幕组（kamigami.org）制作，仅供交流学习，禁止用于任何商业用途
日听:aimie king  翻译:念白白 poopy   校对:木落 时间轴:wcaster
この天守閣で待つ真田幸村
Sanada Yukimura waits atop that castle.
幸村を倒す事こそ　我らが勤め
Defeating Yukimura is our duty!
わかってるでしょうね
You know the job of the Flower Group
私達華組といろり達月組の役目
and that of Irori and the Moon Group, right?
Yes, it's to make sure the servant
and the Moon Group—
はい　お付きの方達雪組…
バカ　声がでかい
Idiot, you're too loud.
It's to buy time for the
Snow Group to complete its task.
雪組がお勤めを果たすまでの時間稼ぎなんだからね
急ぐわよ
Let's hurry.
まだ蟲人は二匹しか倒してないんだから
We've only defeated two Insect-men.
はい
Yes.
The Compassion Slash
That Cuts G!!
そうであったか
I see.
奈阿姫様が自らこの和歌山城の地下にいらっしゃるとは
So Princess Naa herself is
beneath Wakayama Castle.
またとない良き機会を
This is the best chance I'll ever get.
これは　恋川殿の太刀筋
This is Koikawa-dono's style...
We'll follow him.
追いかけるわよ
Illusion magic?
幻術　ですか
Of course.
当たり前でしょう
But we defeated Kirigakure Saizou.
Shouldn't the illusion be undone?
しかし　霧隠才蔵を倒したのですから幻術が解けるのでは
そうよね
Yeah, that's true...
Perhaps the illusion is fading
slowly, like a lifting fog...
霧が晴れるように　ゆっくり幻術が解けているかもしれない
いえ　幻術自体が嘘まやかし
No, the illusions themselves are lies.
それを操る才蔵の言葉を信じるのは
At least, according to their creator, Saizou.
No way!
まさか
お春殿
Oharu-dono!
仁兵衛様
Jinbei-sama!
お帰りが遅いので来ちゃいました
You took so long, I came here.
What?
なんと
仁兵衛様の為に　ほーら　こんなにお団子も
Look at the dumplings I made for you.
Wow! Wow!
なんと　なんと
早く早く　早く
Come on, come on! Come on!
I'm on my way now!
今　参ります
幻術に鼻の下伸ばして
He's getting horny over an illusion.
Stupid Tsukishima!
バカ月島
どうなってるの
What's going on?
幻術です
An illusion.
どうだっていいじゃねーか
It doesn't matter.
こうやって敵の本丸に乗り込んだんだ
We're inside the enemy castle...
言っとくが　てめぇら　今度は俺が行かせてもらうぜ
This time, I'm going on ahead, guys.
When I cut through it, we'll know
if it's an illusion or not.
幻術かそうじゃねーか　切って見りゃわかる
手応えあり　こっちだぜ
I could feel its weight.
This way...
恋川殿に　従いましょう
Let us follow Koikawa-dono.
お春殿かと思えば蟲人であったか
I thought that was Oharu-dono,
but it was Insect-men!
南無
Praise Buddha!
出て来やがれ　俺がぶった切ってやる
Come out, so I can slice you in half.
誰もいねーのかよ
Isn't anyone home?
くそ
Damn it.
恋川殿　バツです　もうすこし冷静に対処してください
That's wrong, Koikawa-dono.
Please try to remain calm.
俺がやりてぇからやる　それだけだ
I want to do this.
That's all it is.
まったく　勝手なんだから
Honestly, you're so selfish.
火鉢
Hibachi?
月島殿は
Where's Tsukishima-dono?
バカ月島は幻術に巻かれたわ
Stupid Tsukishima was fooled by an illusion.
You can hear me, can't you, insects?
聞こえてんだろ　蟲ケラ
バレバレだよ
Your illusion ain't working.
えげつねー血の匂いがすぐそばでプンプンするさ
I can smell fresh blood nearby.
まさかビビっちまったのか
Are you frightened?
I'll fight you!
俺が相手してやるぜ
Very well.
いいだろう
我らは何者も拒まない
We fear nothing.
月島
Tsukishima!
What's wrong, kid?
兄さん　どうした
K-Koikawa-dono, they're strong...
恋川殿　相手は強いです
They?
相手
Looks like you'll be some entertainment.
ちっとは　手応えありそうだな
Be careful.
気を付けて　そいつら脱皮すると強くなるのよ
When they shed their skins,
their strength increases!
More illusions?
またしても幻術ですか
大丈夫　月島
Are you okay, Tsukishima?
That was wrong, Tsukishima-dono.
月島殿　バツです
Any wounded will slow us down.
傷ついたものは足手まといです
Hey, that's an unkind way to put it.
ちょ　ひどい言い方ね
ひ　火鉢殿
H-Hibachi-dono...
Hibachi-do—
火鉢殿
You pervert!
このエロ助が
Hibachi-dono...
火鉢殿　大岡殿のおっしゃる通りです
Oooka-dono is correct.
今は幸村を倒す時
Right now, our goal is defeating Yukimura!
月島
Tsukishima...
However, I am a member
of the Insect Magistrate's...
しかし　自分とで蟲奉行所の一人
I shall not slow you down!
足手まといなどにはなりません
月島
Tsukishima...
Ouch...
お前らは先に行け　ここは俺に任せろ
You guys, go on ahead!
Leave this to me.
Koikawa-dono...
恋川殿
バツです
That's wrong.
その言葉は死亡フラグです
When people say that,
it's a harbinger of death.
大岡殿
Oooka-dono!
恋川殿なら脂肪クラゲなど切って捨てますよ
Koikawa-dono is strong enough
to overcome a herring of death!
皆さん　参ります
Let's go, everyone.
チョロチョロしてんじゃねーよ
Stop wasting my time...
I know you're there!
居るのはわかってるんだぜ
Praise to Amida Buddha.
南無阿弥陀仏
拙僧は真田十傑蟲の一人　三好青海入道
I am one of the Ten Crucifix Insects,
Ten Crucifix Insects
TMiyoshi Seikai Nyuudou
Miyoshi Seikai Nyuudou.
Ten Crucifix Insects
Miyoshi Isa Nyuudou
同じく　三好伊三入道
And I am Miyoshi Isa Nyuudou.
死者の列に加わる前に聞いておこう
Before you join the ranks of
the dead, we shall ask you...
お主　名をなんと申す
What is your name?
あー　別にいいわ
Forget it.
Giving my name to those who will be dead
in a few minutes is a waste of time.
すぐ死んじまうお前らに名乗るの面倒だからよ
てめぇら　脱皮するとえれー強くなるみたいだな
I heard you guys get really strong
when you shed your skins...
But if you die before you can,
wouldn't that be it?
だけどその前に死んじまったらそこでおしまいなんだろ
な…
I'm right, huh?
図星かよ
In that case...
だったらよ　悪いが今すぐ脱皮してくれや
How about just shedding your skins now?
I don't want this ending too fast.
あんまり早く終わっちまったら つまんねーだろ
This isn't my lucky day...
あー　ついてねーや
これで終わりかよ
That's the end.
That won't work...
効かぬ
It won't work at all.
効かぬぞ
Our bodies are those of G, meaning cock...
拙僧達の体躯はG　すなわちゴキ　ブリ
...roaches.
昆虫一の生命力を持つ
We are the hardest to kill of all insects.
拙僧達の再生力の前ではお主の攻撃など
With our regenerative ability, your attacks...
...hurt less than a mosquito bite.
蚊に刺される痛みほども感じぬ
南無阿弥陀仏
Praise to Amida Buddha.
そうこなくちゃいけねぇや
That's more like it.
弱すぎる
Too weak.
That's wrong, Oooka-dono!
バツです　大岡殿
恋川殿が弱くなったという今のお言葉　取り消してください
Take back what you said about
Koikawa-dono being weaker.
恋川殿が負ける所など無涯殿が負けるのと同じぐらい想像できません
I can't imagine Koikawa-dono losing
any more than I can Mugai-dono!
蟲人に対して唯一の不安材料は恋川殿自身です
Regarding the Insect-men, my one
fear is Koikawa-dono himself.
Everyone who knew him long ago,
昔の恋川殿を知る者達は
今の恋川殿を見て口々にこう言います
but sees him now, says the same thing...
蟲奉行所に入った恋川春菊は　以前より遥かに弱くなったと
That Koikawa Shungiku is far weaker now
than he was before he joined the Magistrate's.
You do not even warrant the
Crucifix Insects' attention.
十傑蟲の拙僧達が相手にする程の事も無い
このような弱き者を相手にする拙僧達こそ哀れ
We should be pitied for having
to fight one so weak.
ぬかしあがれ
Shut up!
Repentance Slash!
懺切り
いくら大岡殿でも恋川殿を侮辱することは自分が許しませんよ
I won't let anyone insult
Koikawa-dono, not even you.
バツですよ　月島殿
That is wrong, Tsukishima-dono...
Please do not misunderstand.
勘違いしないでください
確かに　今の恋川殿は十分強い
It's true that he's currently very strong.
But the famous criminal, the Killer of 99,
ただ　悪鬼羅刹九十九斬りの大悪人
恋川春菊は今の姿がかすむほど　鮮烈なまでに強すぎたのです
was far stronger than the man you know.
It's useless.
無駄よ
無駄
Useless.
No slash can damage us.
拙僧達にはあらゆる斬撃が効かぬ
Damn it, they keep regenerating.
クソ　斬っても斬っても再生しやがれ
Fine, then!
こうなったら
Turning your back on an enemy is cowardly!
敵に背を向けるとは卑怯なり
武士の風上にも置けぬ
You are a failure as a samurai.
Sorry, but I'm no samurai...
残念ながら武士じゃねぇんだよ
He's a fast runner,
あやつ逃げ足だけは早いな
だが　拙僧達がGであることを理解しておらん
but he fails to understand
that we are cockroaches.
南無阿弥陀仏
Praise to Amida Buddha.
Did you think you could escape?
逃げられると思ったか
It's simple for us to follow.
我ら壁を這い上がるなど易きこと
I didn't forget you were cockroaches.
おめぇらがGだってことは忘れてねぇよ
だがな
But...
Slice and dice!
ぶったぎる
いくらGでも斬られりゃ落ちるさ
Even a cockroach will fall
when it's cut to pieces.
なるほど
I understand.
闇雲に逃げただけではなかったか
Then you didn't merely run.
しかし拙僧達の力を 侮るな
But do not underestimate...
...our power.
Crap.
やっべ
Too slow!
遅い
かなり効いたぜ
That hurt...
Interesting.
なかなか面白い
Among humans, those skills
and power are rare.
人には稀な力と技
それに感じる同じにおい
And you have the same scent.
これなら拙僧達 脱皮して見せてもよいぞ
Very well,
we shall shed our skins.
Praise to Amida Buddha.
南無阿弥陀仏
These are our true forms!
これこそが拙僧達の真の姿
再生能力は先ほどまでの五倍
Our regenerative capabilities are five times
that which they were a moment ago.
貴様の名を死者の列に加えてやろう
We shall add your name
to the ranks of the dead.
といっても名は知らんがな
Though I suppose we do not know it...
What's that noise?
何の騒ぎでしょう
分かりません
I do not know.
これも幻術の一つか
Perhaps another illusion?
恋川殿が蟲人と戦っているのか
Or Koikawa-dono fighting the Insect-men?
それです
That's it...
なぜ恋川殿が蟲奉所に入ってから　弱くなったというのですか
Why do you say Koikawa-dono has become
weaker since joining the Magistrate's?
Because...
それは…
Because he thought his
father killed his mother.
恋川殿は父親が母親を殺した下手人と思い込み
And Koikawa was following him.
彼の後を追ったのです
その行く手を阻む者を　恋川殿は次々と切り捨てました
He killed anyone who got in his way,
whether government or otherwise.
奉行所の人間だろうが誰であろうが
しかし　ついに追い詰めた時
But when Koikawa finally tracked him down,
父親が下手人ではないと分かったのです
he realized that his father was not behind it.
Until he located his father,
he was strong as an ogre.
父親を追い詰めるまでは　悪鬼羅刹の如き強さでした
しかし　それからの恋川殿は 目的を失ってしまったんです
However, after that, he lost his goal.
人斬りは人斬りであってこそ強いのです
A killer is only strong as his kills.
どうした
What's wrong?!
You smell of blood,
貴様からは血のにおいがする
the smell of a murderer!
人斬りのにおいだ
しかし　数はまだまだ足りん
But you haven't slain enough.
せいぜいが百人か
A hundred, at most?
I'm sure the first murder was terrifying...
一人目は恐ろしかったろう
二人目は更に恐ろしかったろう
The second even more so.
だが三人を過ぎると　恐ろしくなくなる
But after the third, it wasn't frightening at all.
十人を過ぎると　楽しくなる
After ten, it was fun.
そんなことはねぇ
No way.
嘘をつき
Liar...
Each time you killed a man,
you must have felt it.
一人斬るごとに思ったはずだ
自分の技が冴えていく喜びに震えたはずだ
The pleasure of your skills strengthening.
The feeling you derived from your
katana surely became enjoyment!
刀から伝わる感触が　快感になったはずだ
It hurt...
苦しくて
苦くて
It was so bitter.
息ができねぇほどだ
I couldn't even breathe.
しかも親父のあの顔
And the face of my father...
He wanted me to spare him.
俺に助けてくれって
To forgive him.
許してくれって
He actually cried.
涙を流しやがるんだ
あの親父がだぜ
My father, of all people.
A man who'd done nothing but beat me.
俺を殴るか蹴るかしかしなかったあいつが
俺を恐怖で支配してきたやつが
A man who'd ruled my life through terror.
俺に命乞いしやがった
He was begging me for his life.
しかし　人斬りとしてはまだまだ
But as a murderer, you are incomplete.
百を超え　千を超えれば何も感じなくなる
Beyond a hundred or a thousand,
you will cease to feel at all.
もはや数さえどうでもよい
The number will cease to matter.
人の命の儚さだけが　手の中に残る
Only the fragility of human life
will remain in your hands.
南無阿弥陀仏
Praise to Amida Buddha.
だからおめぇら蟲ケラなんだよ
That's why you're only insects...
Hmm?
Poor fool.
哀れな
そのまま死に行けば楽なものを
It would be so much easier
to simply lie there and die.
うっせぇ
Shut up!
数さえどうでもいい
It doesn't matter how many you slay?
人の命を奪っておいて何抜かしてやがる
What are you saying,
having taken someone's life?!
ああ　俺は人斬りさ
That's right, I'm a killer.
多くの命をこの手にかけたよ
I've taken many lives with my own hands.
その手がな 奪った命の数だけ重いんだよ
And the more lives I take,
the heavier those hands feel!
鉛のように　地獄のように重いんだよ
Heavy like lead... Heavy like Hell!
だからまだまだだと
Because you haven't killed enough.
Another five hundred and they'll feel lighter.
後五百人も斬れば軽くなる
These arms will never feel lighter,
何百人斬ろうと　この腕は軽くならねぇ
no matter how many hundreds I kill...
俺はこの重さを背負って生きていくんだ
I'll live with this weight for the rest of my life!
How sad. How sad, indeed.
哀れなり　哀れなり
迷える者を救うのも
Saving the lost...
拙僧達の務め
...is our task.
南無阿弥陀仏
Praise to Amida Buddha.
Praise to Amida Buddha...
南無阿弥陀仏×Ｎ
俺はあの時から
Ever since that day...
「今刀を振り下ろせば　父親と同じ道を歩むと分かったんだ」
"I knew if I brought down my blade,
I'd be following the same path as my father."
と恋川殿はおっしゃっていました
That is what he said.
A heart of compassion?
慈悲の心ですか
慈悲かどうか分かりません
I don't know if it's compassion.
もっとすごいものを得たのです
I think it's something beyond that.
俺は蟲ケラじゃねぇ
I'm not an insect...
I'm an insect-slayer!
蟲斬りになったんだ
What is this?
これは
五倍の再生能力が
Our regenerative speed is five times faster...
But it isn't fast enough!
間に合わぬ
慈合い斬り
Compassion Slash!
生きてやるよ
I'll keep on living...
ずっと　ずっとな
For a long, long time.
Koikawa-dono!
恋川殿
What are you doing here?
どうしてここに
What happened to the Insect-men?
蟲人はどうなりました
Killed two of 'em...
やったよ　二匹な
What? Then that makes four!
なんと　これで四匹目ですね
Three remain and then, Sanada Yukimura.
残りは後三匹と真田幸村
There's still a long way to go.
まだ先は長いです
Justice awaits.
ジャスティスは待っているぞ
My name is Anayama Justice Kosuke.
Next Time
俺は穴山ジャスティス小介
Then I'm Tsukishima Shining Star Jinbei...
ならば自分の二つ名は月島綺羅星仁兵衛
And that's Loincloth Ninja Hibachi-dono!
あちらは褌忍者火鉢殿だ
素敵
Wonderful.
じゃない
No!
Next time, on Mushibugyou:
次回　蟲奉行「どっちが正義！？天間とジャスティス」
Who Is Righteous!? Tenma and Justice!
Who Is Righteous?
Tenma and Justice.